<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Complex Ecological Systems Lab</title><link>http://complexecolab.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Complex Ecological Systems Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://complexecolab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/andrewberdahl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/andrewberdahl/</guid><description>Andrew is broadly interested in ecological systems, but currently focus mainly on problems at the interface of collective behavior and movement ecology. He applies a wide range of techniques (theoretical modeling, numerical simulations, lab experiments and field-work) to explore topics including:
collective search, sensing and navigation, the role of collective decision making (both spatial and temporal) in animal migration, the implications of group-level behaviors on ecological and evolutionary processes, the joint evolution of dispersal and local adaptation Andrew did his postdoc at the Santa Fe Institute and then wrote some papers about collective behavior that all his grad students think are the coolest, so here we are working in his lab.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/annepolyakov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/annepolyakov/</guid><description>Anne Polyakov is a PhD candidate within the Quantitative Ecology and Resource Management Program at the University of Washington, an interdisciplinary program focused on the application of advanced statistical tools to address complex ecological systems. Anne&amp;rsquo;s research involves using statistical analysis and ecological modeling to understand ecological processes, with an emphasis on biodiversity conservation and the role of microbial functions in forest carbon and nitrogen cycling.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/benkoger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/benkoger/</guid><description>Ben works on creating systems that allow for the easy and automated study of large animal groups in the wild. In fact, the tagline of his website is &amp;ldquo;Creating drone and deep learning based systems for studying animal groups in the wild.&amp;rdquo; He went up to Alaska with Andrew this summer and filmed a ton of footage of salmon in rivers and streams in 4K and now plans to use the absolutely massive computer in his office to work on computer vision about it.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/mariakuruvilla/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/mariakuruvilla/</guid><description>Maria studies how environmental and social factors affect how fish move.
In her first project she studied how temperature affects the ability of a school of fish to respond to a predator. She used lab experiments, videos of fish swimming, and computer vision software to track the fish. She found that how temperature affects their swimming speed and acceleration depends on whether they are trying to escape from a predator or not.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/connieokasaki/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/connieokasaki/</guid><description>Connie&amp;rsquo;s general research interests include bridging the gaps between mechanistic modeling, spatial statistics, and constrained optimization. She is particularly&amp;hellip; and then that&amp;rsquo;s where her website cuts off. (Connie if you see this, I think your github.io page is down.)
Connie is a board game player extraordinaire. She has a backpack that can hold upwards of 30 games in organized little pockets or drawers.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/hungminhsu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/hungminhsu/</guid><description>Hung-Min Hsu is now a senior research scientist at AIWaysion Inc.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/arialbrewer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/arialbrewer/</guid><description>Arial is broadly interested in the ecology, behavior, communication, and sociality of marine mammals. For her PhD, she is investigating the vocal behavior, intra-population genetic structure, and epidermal microbial patterns of the endangered Cook Inlet beluga whale population. She is also a marine mammal biologist at NOAA and studies the acoustic ecology of cetaceans in the North Pacific.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/brendanwallace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/brendanwallace/</guid><description>Brendan is interested in complex systems, network science, and general patterns in movement of people and animals. His background is in applied math and computer science. Before UW, he worked on modeling traffic for Google maps. He&amp;rsquo;s currently working on introducing risk-structure and movement frequency to an epidemiological model.
Brendan loves board games, ultimate frisbee, talking about why cars are the worst, and talking about why Golang is the best and everyone should learn it.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/willoestreich/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/willoestreich/</guid><description>Will splits time between our lab and a lab you could arguably call &amp;ldquo;the place where he&amp;rsquo;s actually a postdoctoral researcher,&amp;rdquo; the Monterey Bay Aquarium Research Institute. Will studies collective behavior, migratory patterns, the ways animals produce and use information, and the ways that information may be socially available – for example, if whales &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo; by listening to the reverberations of their echolocating clicks, but can hear eachother&amp;rsquo;s echolocating clicks, in a way they can see what eachother are seeing.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/isobelread/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/isobelread/</guid><description>Isobel is an undergraduate in the Environmental Science and Terrestrial Resource Management (ESRM) program, and may just be one of the most put-together undergraduates you&amp;rsquo;ve ever met. Isobel has lived all over the world, plays in two different rock bands, and last quarter set an intention of learning Spanish on Duolingo.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/bibipowersmccormack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://complexecolab.github.io/people/bibipowersmccormack/</guid><description>Bibi is a computational ecologist exploring movement ecology from an interdisciplinary perspective, seeking to understand how individual animal movements scale up to reveal population patterns and ecosystem health. Bibi started graduate school in Fall 2025 co-advised by Andrew Berdahl and Julia Parrish.
Before grad school, Bibi studied the effects of climate change on river ecosystems with the Pacific Northwest National Laboratory (PNNL) and spatiotemporal changes in global seagrass presence with the Smithsonian Environmental Research Center (SERC).</description></item></channel></rss>